MARISSA MERKT

SUMMARY

Versatile writer and editor whose diversified experience has created a deep appreciation and understanding of the written word. Has successfully adapted copy into the best form for the platform, from collaborating on brand social media strategy to captivating readers with hyper-local journalism.

EMPLOYMENT

CopyPress

Copywriter · Feb. 2021 to Current · Remote

Write clear, actionable copy that is free of redundancies, filler content and grammatical errors.

Collaborate with in-house editors and the project manager from article creation to client approval.

Revise copy based on internal and client feedback.

Meet article goal of writing 3,000 words a day.

Brunswick Beacon

Staff writer/editor · Mar. 2020 to Feb. 2021 · Shallotte, NC

Captivated readers with coverage of events and organizations in the area.

Informed the public of important government changes relevant to them in an easy-to-read format. Edited copy to ensure it abided by AP guidelines, avoided grammatical errors and followed the newspaper's voice.

Cider Spoon Stories

Intern · Feb. 2019 to May 2019 · Austin, TX

Collaborated to develop brand strategy to effectively promote services in an engaging way.

Effectively copy-edited manuscripts for ghostwriting services and collaborated with head editor to deliver flawless products.

Successfully organized events to gain brand exposure.

Brittany's Hope

Intern · May 2016 to Aug. 2016 · Elizabethtown, PA

Collaborated with the communications manager to build awareness of the nonprofit's mission.

Researched and wrote content for newsletters, email updates and press releases.

EDUCATION

Fort Hays State University

Grant Writing Certification 2021

Shippensburg University · 2013 to 2017

Bachelors in Communications

SKILLS

Organization, Time management, AP style, InDesign, Research skills, Canva